Miguel Angel Guerra Chamorro

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Electronic engineer dedicated to frontend development with +2 years of experience able to carry out complete projects from scratch and create end-to-end solutions including hardware implementation. Having developed for companies and also as a freelancer, it is possible to combine the main skills of each work style, achieving effective collaboration in multidisciplinary teams but also the ability to be autonomous when facing challenges.

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack developer at Fireno SAS

Multiple software tools were developed from scratch focused on the company's internal administrative and engineering sectors, contributing to achieving better teamwork practices. It was possible to autonomously develop interfaces capable of satisfying the needs of different projects and which are still an important part of the company today. In addition, it was possible to contribute ideas that allowed us to significantly improve the productivity and usability of the tools created for the company, allowing us to play a key role in the planning and design of the projects.

February 2021 - January 2023 · 2 years · [Barranquilla, Colombia] [Fire suppression systems company]

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Contribute ideas and suggestions to the company from my point of view as a developer in order to improve the performance of the developed tools.
- Organize and guarantee compliance with delivery times in the different stages of product development.
- Develop clean and scalable code to be implemented in different projects
- Validate the correct functioning of the tools developed through the implementation of software tests capable of detecting errors in the implementation of the code.
- Effectively communicate step by step in the development of the application to the different parties involved in the project (developers, designers, manager, etc.)

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

• The times and quality of customer service were improved by reducing the list of possibilities when diagnosing problems remotely in fire suppression devices from 6

- possibilities to a specific one, by implementing functions that allowed analysis of the parameters of the device and detect the problem presented.
- The productivity of the company was improved by the development of multiple tools used for management and monitoring of internal activities.
- The performance of a real-time alert monitoring project was improved by reducing the consumption of computing resources by implementing web sockets instead of periodic alert status update functions.

Front-End developer a freelancer

As a freelancer, I have worked on various projects for different clients, which has allowed me to acquire extensive experience in technologies and tools for frontend development. I have learned to communicate effectively with my clients, witnessing the positive changes in their businesses with the creation of an online tool. I am excited to continue to grow and learn to collaborate with new clients in the future.

January 2023 - Now 2 months · [Barranquilla, Colombia]

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Development and maintenance of websites for clients using the latest technologies to provide a product with the best quality and durability.
- Create attractive and easy-to-use user interface designs that meet the needs and objectives of the client.
- Speed and performance optimization to ensure websites are fast and run smoothly by optimizing images, minimizing code, among other optimization techniques.
- Perform testing and debugging to ensure that websites work properly on a variety of browsers and devices.
- Update and maintain the content of the website according to the needs of the client.
- Maintain clear and constant communication with the customer to ensure that their needs and goals are met.

KEY ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Designing and developing an eCommerce website for a client that increased sales by 50% in the first month after launch.
- Maintain constant communication with the client which resulted in a 100% retention rate over a period of 2 months.
- Implement security measures that have kept the number of security breaches on the website at 0%.

EDUCATION

Electronic engineer at Universidad del Norte

As an electronic engineering student, you appreciate software as a fundamental tool in the design and implementation of electronic systems. During my university education, I have acquired knowledge in programming languages such as C++, Python and Javascript, which I have used to develop applications and solutions in different areas. In addition, it is possible to work on interdisciplinary projects that teach the importance of collaboration and teamwork in the development of innovative technological solutions.

June 2017 - May 2022 [Barranquilla, Colombia]

LANGUAGES

Spanish and English.

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript
- React
- React native
- Node JS
- JSON
- Tailwind CSS
- Next JS